＜５年以下の懲役 または➡
50万円以下の
罰金に処せられます＞
＜後悔しても 元には戻せない＞
不正視聴!?
(ウタカタ)お前たち！
You people...
(ナルト)大丈夫か？
ああ。
Are you all right?
Yeah...
でも なんでここに？
やっぱり ホタルが気になって？
But why are you here?
You were also worried about Hotaru?
Yeah right. It was just
sheer coincidence.
なわけがないだろう。
たまたまだ。
だが コイツらは
ホタルを追ってきたんじゃない。
But...these guys didn't come here
for Hotaru.
どういうことだ？
それに コイツら…。
What do you mean?
And who are these guys?
《ヤマト : あの面は…。
That mask...
そうか 狙いは…》
I see... So they're target is...
(ホタル)師匠!!
Master!
《どうして 木ノ葉が…》
Why are the Hidden Leaf here?
その子を離してもらいましょう。
ならぬ。
Please let that girl go.
No!
だったら ムリやりにでも
その子を返してもらうまでだ！
In that case! We'll take her back...
by force!
影分身の術！
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
(サイ)忍法 超獣戯画！
Ninja Art!
Super Beast Scroll!
オレは 真ん中のヤツをいく。
I'll take the one in the middle.
お前は その周りを
抑えてくれ。
You take the ones around him.
We'll attack together.
一気にやるってばよ！
わかった。 だが この暗部は…。
Got it. But...these Black Ops are...
もう少し 様子を見よう。
Let's see how it goes for
a bit longer...
《ヤツらの目的を
確かめなければ》
We need to find out what
their purpose is.
Master...
(ホタル)師匠…。
秘術 切雨！
Hidden Jutsu: Kirisame!
何だ この雨は!?
What's with this rain?!
コイツは チャクラに反応し削り取る
切雨の術だ。
It's a jutsu that eats away the chakra
it comes into contact with.
It's called the Kirisame Jutsu!
この！
Why you...!
いけ！
Go!
ダメだ！ 早まるな！
Stop! Don't be hasty!
いくぞ！
水流鞭！
Let's go!
Water Whip!
木遁の術！
Wood Style!
師匠!!
Master!
キャー！
しばらく
おとなしくしてもらおう。
I need you to stay quiet
for a while.
What the hell are you doing?!
何てことしやがる！
(ヤマト)ナルト！
Naruto!
待て。
Wait.
我らは任務により その子を
警護している途上にあります。
We are on a mission to guard
that girl.
どうか お返し願いたい。
Please return her to us.
そうだ！ 返せよ コラ！
Yeah! Give her back, you!
あなた方 霧隠れの暗部が
求めているのは➡
You are Anbu Black Ops
from the Hidden Mist,
ここにおられる ウタカタさんですね。
and the one you seek
is this man, correct?
え… 霧隠れの暗部!?
Huh? Anbu Black Ops...
from the Hidden Mist?
I get it now...
《なるほど…
ってことは コイツは》
So that means he is a...
Utakata is a Rogue Ninja from
the Hidden Mist
ウタカタさんは ビンゴブックにも載っている
霧隠れの抜け忍。
and is listed in the Bingo Book.
彼らは それを追ってきた
追い忍ですよ。
These men have come after him.
そんじゃあ コイツらは➡
So these guys...
aren't ninjas who are after her?
あの子を追っている
忍じゃねえってことか。
ウタカタを…。
They're after Utakata?
その子は 関係ない。
離してください。
She has nothing to do with you.
Please release her.
Then we'll exchange her for him.
ならば その者を
こちらに引き渡していただこうか。
(ヤマト)いいえ。
No.
それはできません。
なにっ!?
That, we can't do.
What?!
その子は この方を
特に慕っているようで➡
That girl seems to be very fond
of this man.
If we hand him over to you,
no doubt, she will pursue you.
そちらに引き渡したら
間違いなく➡
あなた方を 追っていくでしょう。
Then we'll be in trouble.
そうなったら 我々が困る。
だから この方は渡せない。
So we can't turn him over.
ならば… 我らも！
Then...neither can we...
武力での対決となると➡
If we resort to force,
里を越え 国どうしの争いに
発展するかもしれませんよ。
it may have major effects
beyond this village,
and erupt into a full-scale war.
そこまでの お覚悟を？
Are you willing to go that far?
《シラナミ : 霧隠れが…》
The Hidden Mist?
ヤマト隊長…。
Captain Yamato.
Men of the Hidden Leaf...
≪木ノ葉の方々。
(ツルギ)私は
この部隊を影によりて預かる者。
I command this unit from
behind the scenes.
霧隠れの暗部頭 ツルギと申す。
I am Tsurugi, head of
the Hidden Mist Anbu Black Ops.
国どうしの争いに発展することは
私どもとて 本意ではない。
It is certainly not our desire
to escalate this
into a war between nations.
交渉の余地は
まだ あるように思うが？
Certainly, we can still negotiate?
えぇ 私も。
Yes, I agree.
アンタは…。
You're...
しばし 申し合わせを。
Let us meet. Just you and I...
あなたと私…。
そして ウタカタとで…。
And Utakata.
わかりました。
Understood.
２人は ここで待機！
You two stay here.
"Rogue Ninja's Past"
では あなた方が
その任務を終えるまで しばし➡
Then until you complete
your mission,
ウタカタ捕縛の手を
休めることにしよう。
we will postpone
apprehending Utakata.
あの子の安全が 確保できしだい➡
As soon as her safety
is guaranteed,
あなたに知らせましょう。
I will notify you.
約束を違えたときは➡
Please keep in mind that should
you go back on our agreement,
国どうしの争いも
辞さぬ覚悟がある。
そのことを
覚えておいてもらおう。
war between our nations
may be inevitable.
わかっています。
I understand.
ふうん。
Hmm...
どちら様も 大仰な。
You guys are too much.
I'll be doing things as I please.
オレはオレで 勝手にやらせてもらう。
そうはいかないよ。
Not likely.
(ヤマト)任務が終わるまでは
我々と 行動を共にしてもらう。
Until our mission is over,
you will remain with us.
ただ そのあとは
あなたと 霧隠れの方々の問題だ。
After that, it's all between you
and the Hidden Mist.
わかった。
Fine.
あなた…➡
Tell me...
霧隠れで
いったい 何があったんです？
Just what did you do
in Hidden Mist Village?
それ以上は 出過ぎているぞ。
That...is none of your business.
すみません。
My apologies.
しばし ２人だけで…。
I want to speak to him alone.
向こうで待っています。
I'll wait over there.
ヤマト隊長。
話し合いは？
Captain Yamato!
How did your talk go?
まぁ うまくいった。
Oh, it went well.
２人は？
Where are those two?
少し 話があるそうだ。
Having a discussion.
ウタカタが… アイツが抜け忍ってのは➡
Is it true...
that Utakata is a Rogue Ninja?
本当なのか？
ああ。
Yeah...
もう わずらわせるな。
Don't give us trouble.
Return to the Hidden Mist.
戻ってこい。 霧隠れに。
フン… 嫌ですよ。
Humph! No thanks!
なんで わざわざ殺されに…。
Why would I go back
just to get killed...?
里も変わった。
The village has changed.
血霧の里と呼ばれたころの
悪しき習慣もなくなり➡
We no longer have the practices
that once gave us the nickname,
今や 平和に見える。
"Blood Mist Village."
しかし それも 五大国の
ギリギリのパワーバランスの上に➡
But while things may seem peaceful,
it is a delicate power balance
between the Five Great Nations.
成り立っているにすぎない。
お前の重要性は 年ごとに増し➡
The importance of what you possess
increases each year,
その力も研究を重ねている。
and research into its use
has also been stepped up.
里としても
お前の力を必要としている今➡
The village needs that power,
so you certainly won't be killed.
よもや 殺されることはない。
もう 人を信じることはしない！
I don't trust anyone anymore.
((ウタカタ : 師匠… やめてくれ！
Master... Please stop, Master!
師匠！
ぐっ… あぁ～!!
(うわぁ～っ!!))
師匠は オレを殺そうとした。
My master...tried to kill me...
オレの中の アイツもろとも…。
along with that thing inside me.
((うわぁ～っ!!))
里のために
この身を犠牲にしたオレを…。
I sacrificed myself for the sake
of the village.
師匠の言葉を信じ
受け入れた このオレを…。
I trusted my master's words...
and did as he bid.
その想いごと
ヤツは殺そうとしたんだ！
And he betrayed my trust...
he tried to kill me!
((うわぁ～っ！
(ハルサメ)何!?
What?!
(ハルサメ)これは… この力は…。
Th-This...power...
(待て！ 止まれ！ 止まれ～!!))
Wait!
Stop! Stop!
違う ウタカタ。 ヤツは…➡
No, Utakata! He didn't...
ハルサメは お前を
殺そうとしたわけじゃない。
Harusame didn't try to kill you.
そうじゃないんだ。
It wasn't like that.
お前に施してしまった
あの呪われた所行…。
That cursed deed he performed on you...
それを引き離そうとしたのだ。
He was trying to separate it
from you.
お前を助けようと…。
He was trying to save you.
フン！ そんな話 誰が信じる？
Like I'd believe such a story...
あなたも もうろくしたものだ。
You've grown senile.
本当の話だ。
I speak the truth...
師匠は… いや あの男は➡
My master... No, that man used me
and tried to kill me.
オレを利用し 殺そうとした。
そして その果てに ヤツは死んだ。
And in the aftermath...he died.
里の者に言わせれば オレが
殺したということなんだろうが。
If you ask the villagers,
they will say I killed him.
ウタカタ… 里に戻れ。
Utakata... Return to the village.
そうすれば ワシの言ったことが
本当だとわかる。
Then you will know that
I am not lying.
ごめんだ！
ならば お前には➡
No thanks.
Then, we have no choice
but to kill you.
死んでもらうしかない。
ご自由に。
As you please.
私も自由にやらせてもらいます。
And I will do as I please.
師匠！
Master!
離してやれ。
はっ！
Let her go.
Yes, sir!
師匠！
黙れ！
Master!
Enough!
二度と オレのことを師匠と呼ぶな。
Never call me that again.
わかったな。
Understand?
木ノ葉の方々。
Men of the Hidden Leaf, as agreed,
we will retreat for now.
約束どおり 我らは いったん退く。
互いに任務が
無事完了することを祈ろう。
Let us pray that both our missions
are successful.
ただし 付かず離れずの監視は
続けさせていただく。
However, we will continue to
keep watch over you.
わかりました。
(ツルギ)では…。
Understood.
Farewell.
散！
Scatter!
やれやれ…。
Oh dear...
さて… これから どうしますか。
Now then, where do
we go from here?
土蜘蛛の里には
もう戻らないほうがいいですね。
It's best that we don't return
to the Tsuchigumo village.
うん そうだね。 忍の里の
態をなさないのであれば➡
Yes, you're right.
If it's no longer secure as
a ninja village,
あの子にとって
安全とは言いがたい。
her safety is questionable.
それなら 葛城山に戻って➡
Then it may be better to return
to Mount Katsuragi
体勢を整えたほうが
いいかもしれないね。
and rethink our stance.
私も戻りたい。
遁兵衛の無事な姿が見たい。
I also wish to go back.
I want to make sure Tonbei
is all right.
まぁ あそこも禁術を狙った連中が
戻ってくる可能性もあるし➡
Although, the ones after
the Forbidden Jutsu
may also go back to Katsuragi,
so it may not be safe either.
安全とはいえないが…。
遁兵衛さん サクラと合流して
そのあとのことを考えよう。
Let's join up with
Tonbei and Sakura,
then decide on our course of action.
ウタカタさん あなたもですよ。
Utakata, you too.
はぁ…。
大丈夫か？
うん…。
Are you all right?
Uh-huh...
どうして 師匠って
呼んじゃいけないのかな…。
I wonder why he doesn't want me
to call him "Master."
((ヤツは 師匠殺しのウタカタ。
里を抜けた大罪人だ))
Utakata is a heinous criminal
who killed his master
and escaped from the village.
《ウタカタ様と お師匠さんに…
いったい 何が…》
Just what happened between...
Sir Utakata and his master?
ウタカタと霧隠れの関係は
オレたちにも わかんねえ。
We don't know what
the relationship is
between Utakata and
the Hidden Mist.
けど そんなこたぁどうでもいい。
But that's not important.
お前が 勝手に弟子になる
って決めてんなら➡
If you've already decided
you want to be his student,
それで いいんじゃねえか？
ダメです。
then who cares?
It matters.
I want to become strong.
私は強くなりたい。
一族 再興のために…。
In order to restore my clan's honor.
だから 教えを請いたいの。
That's why I want to
learn from him.
わかるぜ。 手取り足取り
もっと 教えてほしいんだろ？
I can tell. You want him to
teach you hands on, right?
別に そんなわけじゃ…。
It's not like that...
いや オレだって そうだったから。
Well, I felt the same way too.
オレには親の記憶がねえ。
I don't have any memories
of my parents.
え？
だからかな…。
Huh?
So maybe that's why...
when I traveled with the Pervy Sage...
エロ仙人と旅してる間に➡
親がいたら こんなかなぁなんて
勝手に思い込んで➡
I wondered if that's what
it felt like to have a parent.
オレ自身が エロ仙人に
甘えてたのかもしんねえ。
And I acted spoiled
with him sometimes.
けど 修業ってのは
そんなに甘いもんじゃない。
But training isn't that easy.
自分で考え
自分でコツをつかまなけりゃ➡
You have to think things
through yourself,
and learn the technique by yourself.
いつまでたっても 上達できねえ。
Otherwise, you'll never get better.
そんな基本的な考えすら➡
If the Pervy Sage hadn't been there,
エロ仙人がいなきゃ
知らなかったことだ。
I wouldn't even have realized
something that basic.
一人じゃない…。
We're not alone...
Just the thought that
someone is nearby,
誰かがそばにいて
見守ってくれるってだけで➡
watching over us...
that alone makes us strong.
強くなれる気がすんだ。
わかります。
I understand how you feel.
I envy you, Naruto.
私 ナルトさんがうらやましい。
ナルトさんに負けず
私もウタカタ様を師匠として…。
Just like you, I'm going to think of
Sir Utakata as my master and...
Hey...you look pale...
おい お前 顔色が…。
大丈夫…。
I'm...okay...
おい！
Hey!
すごい熱だ。
You're burning up...
ケガしてるじゃねえかよ！
あのときか！
You're hurt!
Is it from that fight?!
ヤマト隊長！
Captain Yamato!
I'll see to her.
オレが診る。
Can you go and get some
medicinal herbs?
薬草を取って来てくれないか。
そうだな ジゴクソバなら
この辺の湿気の多い場所で➡
The dokudami plant should
be abundant around here
in the moist areas.
手に入るはずだ。
It has heart-shaped leaves
which are purple underneath.
ハート形で葉の裏は紫色をしてる。
葉の裏が紫色だな。
The leaves are purple underneath, right?
そうだ。
わかった。
Yes.
All right!
どうしたんです？
What's wrong?
ホタルがケガを。
Hotaru is injured...
外してくれないか。
Let us be.
All right...
わかった。
Moist areas...
湿気が多いところって言ったら➡
I guess I should search
by the riverbank!
やっぱ川原を中心に
探さねえとな。
あった！
There! That's gotta be it.
あれに間違いねえ。
って なんだよ これ！
Huh? What the hell?!
This is a chameleon plant!
ドクダミじゃねえか！
Aw man, there were lots
of 'em along the way!
これなら ここにくるあいだに
いくらでも あったってのに！
クソッ ムダな時間くっちまった。
Damn it!
I wasted so much time!
これは…。
What the...?
なんなんだよ これは。
What the hell is this...?
土蜘蛛一族の秘術は➡
The Forbidden Jutsu of
the Tsuchigumo Clan
ホタルに この子自身に
刻まれていたんだ。
It was engraved...
into this child's very own body.
なんてことを…。
How could they do such a thing?
何が秘術だ 何が一族だ。
To hell with Forbidden Jutsu...
To hell with the clan...
何が師匠だ。
To hell with one's master!
And all these selfish guys who
do atrocious things
身勝手な連中が
従うだけの人間に➡
to those who serve them
without a hint of remorse.
平気で
こんな無残なマネをしやがる。
オレたちを
ただの器としか考えていない。
They think of us...as mere tools.
もの言わぬ器と…。
Tools...who don't speak.
ホタル…。
Hotaru...
なるほど たまには
手作りのプレゼントが効果的か。
おい サイ！
やぁ。
何か用か？
What is this, Tonbei?
いきなり呼び出して。
用ってほどじゃないんだけど。
じゃあ 呼ぶなってばよ。
So En no Gyoja left behind
a way to extract the Forbidden Jutsu.
これ キミのために描いたんだ。
It is evident that our clan
no longer has the strength
もらってくれないかな？
to safeguard the Forbidden Jutsu.
はぁ？
嫌かな？
To prevent its misuse,
we have no choice
but to destroy the jutsu.
嫌って別に嫌だけど…。
Destroy it?
What'll happen to Hotaru then?!
んじゃまぁ くれるって言うなら
遠慮なくもらっとくぜ。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Heir to Darkness"
せっかくだから飾っといてやっか。
ガオ～！
うわっ なんだ!? おい！
Damn it! Isn't there
another way?!
テメエ！ いい加減にしろよ!!
I see...
So sometimes, a hand-made present
is very effective.
Hey, Sai!
Hi.
Has something come up?
Calling me out of the blue like this.
サイの野郎
やってくれるじゃねえか。
It's nothing really...
ナルト 喜んでくれたかな。
Then don't call me.
But I drew this for you.
Will you accept it?
Huh?!
Don't you like it?
(バイロ)落ち着きがないですね カナロア。
No, it's not that...
Well, actually it is...
But guess I'll take it if you insist.
お前も心のざわめきを
感じているのですか…。
He made it for me,
so I'll hang it up somewhere.
(バイロ)そうです これは聖戦。
歯向かうものには
容赦しません。